<cluster xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="zigbee-description.xsd" code="0x0101">
    <name>Door Lock</name>
    <description>The door lock cluster provides an interface to a generic way to secure a door. The physical object that provides the locking functionality is abstracted from the cluster. The cluster has a small list of mandatory attributes and functions and a list of optional features.</description>
	<description>Generally the door lock itself implements the server side of this cluster. The attributes and commands listed in this cluster were developed to be implemented by a door lock which has the ability to keep track of multiple users and schedules.</description>
	<description>The door lock cluster provides several alarms which can be sent when there is a critical state on the door lock. The alarms available for the door lock cluster are listed in the section below outlining the alarm mask at- tribute. The Alarm cluster is used to generate the actual alarms.</description>
	<description>The event mechanism in the door lock centers on the transmission of two commands autonomously generated by the server and sent to a bound device. The assumption is that the binding mechanism will be used to commission the server to send these commands.</description>
	<description>Door locks have the ability to require the use of APS encryption for sending and receiving of all cluster messages. The Security Level attribute is used to specify the type of encryption required by the door lock.</description>
    <command code="0x00" source="client">
        <name>Lock Door Command</name>
		<description>This command causes the lock device to lock the door. As of HA 1.2, this command includes an optional code for the lock. The door lock MAY require a PIN depending on the value of the [Require PIN for RF Operation attribute]</description>
        <field type="OCTET_STRING">
            <name>PIN Code</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x01" source="client">
        <name>Unlock Door Command</name>
		<description>This command causes the lock device to unlock the door. As of HA 1.2, this command includes an optional code for the lock. The door lock MAY require a code depending on the value of the [Require PIN for RF Operation attribute].</description>
		<description>Note: If the attribute AutoRelockTime is supported the lock will close when the auto relock time has expired</description>
        <field type="OCTET_STRING">
            <name>PIN Code</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x02" source="client">
        <name>Toggle</name>
        <description>Request the status of the lock. As of HA 1.2, this command includes an optional code for the lock. The door lock MAY require a code depending on the value of the [Require PIN for RF Operation attribute]</description>
        <field type="CHARACTER_STRING">
            <name>PIN</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x03" source="client">
        <name>Unlock With Timeout</name>
        <description>This command causes the lock device to unlock the door with a timeout parameter. After the time in seconds specified in the timeout field, the lock device will relock itself automatically. This timeout parameter is only temporary for this message transition only and overrides the default relock time as specified in the [Auto Relock Time attribute] attribute. If the door lock device is not capable of or does not want to support temporary Relock Timeout, it SHOULD not support this optional command.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Timeout In Seconds</name>
        </field>
        <field type="CHARACTER_STRING">
            <name>PIN</name>
        </field>
    </command>

    <command code="0x00" source="server">
        <name>Lock Door Response</name>
		<description>This command is sent in response to a Lock command with one status byte payload. The Status field SHALL be set to SUCCESS or FAILURE.</description>
		<description>The status byte only indicates if the message has received successfully. To determine the lock and/or door status, the client SHOULD query to [Lock State attribute] and [Door State attribute]</description>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT">
            <name>Status</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x01" source="server">
        <name>Unlock Door Response</name>
		<description>This command is sent in response to a Toggle command with one status byte payload. The Status field SHALL be set to SUCCESS or FAILURE.</description>
		<description>The status byte only indicates if the message has received successfully. To determine the lock and/or door status, the client SHOULD query to [Lock State attribute] and [Door State attribute].</description>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT">
            <name>Status</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x02" source="server">
        <name>Toggle Response</name>
        <description>This command is sent in response to a Toggle command with one status byte payload. The Status field SHALL be set to SUCCESS or FAILURE.</description>
		<description>The status byte only indicates if the message has received successfully. To determine the lock and/or door status, the client SHOULD query to [Lock State attribute] and [Door State attribute].</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Status</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x03" source="server">
        <name>Unlock With Timeout Response</name>
        <description>This command is sent in response to an Unlock with Timeout command with one status byte payload. The Status field SHALL be set to SUCCESS or FAILURE.</description>
		<description>The status byte only indicates if the message has received successfully. To determine status, the client SHOULD query to [Lock State attribute] and [Door State attribute].</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Status</name>
        </field>
    </command>

    <attribute code="0x0000" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="DoorLockLockStateEnum" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Lock State</name>
        <description>Provides the current lock state</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0001" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT"  class="DoorLockLockTypeEnum" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Lock Type</name>
        <description>Defines the type of lock</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0002" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Actuator Enabled</name>
        <description>Boolean indicating the enabled/disabled state of the lock</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0003" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="DoorLockDoorStateEnum" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Door State</name>
        <description>The current state of the door lock</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0004" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true">
        <name>Door Open Events</name>
        <description>This attribute holds the number of door open events that have occurred since it was last zeroed.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0005" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true">
        <name>Door Closed Events</name>
        <description>This attribute holds the number of door closed events that have occurred since it was last zeroed.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0006" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true">
        <name>Open Period</name>
        <description>This attribute holds the number of minutes the door has been open since the last time it transitioned from closed to open.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0010" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF" default="0x0000">
        <name>Num Lock Records Supported</name>
        <description>The number of available log records.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0011" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF" default="0x0000">
        <name>Num Total Users Supported</name>
        <description>Number of total users supported by the lock. This value is equal to the higher one of [# of PIN Users Supported] and [# of RFID Users Supported]</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0012" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF" default="0x0000">
        <name>Num PIN Users Supported</name>
        <description>The number of PIN users supported.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0013" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF" default="0x0000">
        <name>Num RFID Users Supported</name>
        <description>The number of RFID users supported. </description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0014" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x00">
        <name>Num Weekday Schedules Supported Per User</name>
        <description>The number of configurable week day schedule supported per user.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0015" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x00">
        <name>Num Yearday Schedules Supported Per User</name>
        <description>The number of configurable year day schedule supported per user</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0016" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x00">
        <name>Num Holiday Schedules Supported Per User</name>
        <description>The number of holiday schedules supported for the entire door lock device.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0017" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x08">
        <name>Max PIN Length</name>
        <description>An 8 bit value indicates the maximum length in bytes of a PIN Code on this device. The default is set to 8 since most lock manufacturers currently allow PIN Codes of 8 bytes or less.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0018" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x04">
        <name>Min PIN Length</name>
        <description>An 8 bit value indicates the minimum length in bytes of a PIN Code on this device. The default is set to 4 since most lock manufacturers do not support PIN Codes that are shorter than 4 bytes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0019" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x14">
        <name>Max RFID Code Length</name>
        <description>An 8 bit value indicates the maximum length in bytes of a RFID Code on this device. The value depends on the RFID code range specified by the manufacturer, if media anti-collision identifiers (UID) are used as RFID code, a value of 20 (equals 10 Byte ISO 14443A UID) is recommended.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x001A" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x08">
        <name>Min RFID Code Length</name>
        <description>An 8 bit value indicates the minimum length in bytes of a RFID Code on this device. The value depends on the RFID code range specified by the manufacturer, if media anti-collision identifiers (UID) are used as RFID code, a value of 8 (equals 4 Byte ISO 14443A UID) is recommended.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0020" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Enable Logging</name>
        <description>Enable/disable event logging. When event logging is enabled, all event messages are stored on the lock for retrieval. Logging events can be but not limited to Tamper Alarm, Lock, Unlock, Autolock, User Code Added, User Code Deleted, Schedule Added, and Schedule Deleted. For a full detail of all the possible alarms and events, please refer to the full list in the Alarm and Event Masks Attribute Set.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0021" type="CHARACTER_STRING" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Language</name>
        <description>Modifies the language for the on-screen or audible user interface using three bytes from ISO-639-1. It consists of one byte of length and two bytes for the language code. For example if the language is set to English, the value would be "02 65 6E" for the language code "en"</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0022" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x00">
        <name>LED Settings</name>
        <description>The settings for the LED support three different modes</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0023" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF" default="0x00000000">
        <name>Auto Relock Time</name>
        <description>The number of seconds to wait after unlocking a lock before it automatically locks again. 0=disabled. If set, unlock operations from any source will be timed. For one time unlock with timeout use the specific command.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0024" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x00">
        <name>Sound Volume</name>
        <description>The sound volume on a door lock has three possible settings: silent, low and high volumes</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0025" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="DoorLockOperatingModeEnum" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x00">
        <name>Operating Mode</name>
        <description>Shows the current operating mode</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0026" type="BITMAP_16_BIT"  class="DoorLockSupportedOperatingModesBitmap" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x0001">
        <name>Supported Operating Modes</name>
        <description>This bitmap contains all operating bits of the Operating Mode Attribute supported by the lock. The value of the enumeration in “Operating Mode” defines the related bit to be set, as shown in Table 7-16. All bits supported by a lock SHALL be set to zero.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0027" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x0000">
        <name>Default Configuration Register</name>
        <description>This attribute represents the default configurations as they are physically set on the device (example: hardware dip switch setting, etc…) and represents the default setting for some of the attributes within this Operational Setting Attribute Set (for example: LED, Auto Lock, Sound Volume, and Operating Mode attributes).</description>
		<description>This is a read-only attribute and is intended to allow clients to determine what changes MAY need to be made without having to query all the included attributes. It MAY be beneficial for the clients to know what the device’s original settings were in the event that the device needs to be restored to factory default settings.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0028" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Enable Local Programming</name>
        <description>Enable/disable local programming on the door lock. The local programming features includes but not limited to adding new user codes, deleting existing user codes, add new schedule, deleting existing schedule on the local door lock interfaces. If this value is set to 0x01 or TRUE then local programming is enabled on the door lock. If it is set to 0x00 or FALSE then local programming is disabled on the door lock. Local programming is enabled by default.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0029" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Enable One Touch Locking</name>
        <description>Enable/disable the ability to lock the door lock with a single touch on the door lock. </description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x002A" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Enable Inside Status Led</name>
        <description>Enable/disable an inside LED that allows the user to see at a glance if the door is locked.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x002B" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Enable Privacy Mode Button</name>
        <description>Enable/disable a button inside the door that is used to put the lock into privacy mode. When the lock is in privacy mode it cannot be manipulated from the outside.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0030" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x00">
        <name>Wrong Code Entry Limit</name>
        <description>The number of incorrect codes or RFID presentment attempts a user is allowed to enter before the door will enter a lockout state. The lockout state will be for the duration of UserCodeTemporaryDisableTime.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0031" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x00">
        <name>User Code Temporary Disable Time</name>
        <description>The number of seconds that the lock shuts down following wrong code entry. 1-255 seconds. Device can shutdown to lock user out for specified amount of time. (Makes it difficult to try and guess a PIN for the device.)</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0032" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Send PIN Over The Air</name>
        <description>Boolean set to True if it is ok for the door lock server to send PINs over the air. This attribute determines the behavior of the server’s TX operation. If it is false, then it is not ok for the device to send PIN in any messages over the air.</description>
		<description>The PIN field within any door lock cluster message SHALL keep the first octet unchanged and masks the actual code by replacing with 0xFF. For example (PIN "1234" ): If the attribute value is True, 0x04 0x31 0x32 0x33 0x34 SHALL be used in the PIN field in any door lock cluster message payload. If the attribute value is False, 0x04 0xFF 0xFF 0xFF 0xFF SHALL be used.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0033" type="BOOLEAN" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Require PIN For RF Operation</name>
        <description>Boolean set to True if the door lock server requires that an optional PINs be included in the payload of RF lock operation events like Lock, Unlock and Toggle in order to function.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0034" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>ZigBee Security Level</name>
        <description>Door locks MAY sometimes wish to implement a higher level of security within the application protocol in additional to the default network security. For instance a door lock MAY wish to use additional APS security for cluster transactions. This protects the door lock against being controlled by any other devices which have access to the network key.</description>
		<description>The Security Level attribute allows the door lock manufacturer to indicate what level of security the doorlock requires.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0040" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>Alarm Mask</name>
        <description>The alarm mask is used to turn on/off alarms for particular functions. Alarms for an alarm group are enabled if the associated alarm mask bit is set. Each bit represents a group of alarms. Entire alarm groups can be turned on or off by setting or clearing the associated bit in the alarm mask.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0041" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>Keypad Operation Event Mask</name>
        <description>Event mask used to turn on and off the transmission of keypad operation events. This mask DOES NOT apply to the storing of events in the report table.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0042" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>RF Operation Event Mask</name>
        <description>Event mask used to turn on and off the transmission of RF operation events. This mask DOES NOT apply to the storing of events in the report table.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0043" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>Manual Operation Event Mask</name>
        <description>Event mask used to turn on and off manual operation events. This mask DOES NOT apply to the storing of events in the report table.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0044" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>RFID Operation Event Mask</name>
        <description>Event mask used to turn on and off RFID operation events. This mask DOES NOT apply to the storing of events in the report table.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0045" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>Keypad Programming Event Mask</name>
        <description>Event mask used to turn on and off keypad programming events. This mask DOES NOT apply to the storing of events in the report table.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0046" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>RF Programming Event Mask</name>
        <description>Event mask used to turn on and off RF programming events. This mask DOES NOT apply to the storing of events in the report table.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0047" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0x0000">
        <name>RFID Programming Event Mask</name>
        <description>Event mask used to turn on and off RFID programming events. This mask DOES NOT apply to the storing of events in the report table.</description>
    </attribute>

</cluster>
