<cluster xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="zigbee-description.xsd" code="0x0406">
    <name>Occupancy Sensing</name>
    <description>The cluster provides an interface to occupancy sensing functionality, including configuration and provision of notifications of occupancy status.</description>
    <attribute code="0x0000" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="true">
        <name>Occupancy</name>
        <description>The Occupancy attribute is a bitmap.</description>
        <description>Bit 0 specifies the sensed occupancy as follows: 1 = occupied, 0 = unoccupied. All other bits are reserved.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0001" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Occupancy Sensor Type</name>
        <description>The OccupancySensorType attribute specifies the type of the occupancy sensor.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0010" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFFFE" default="0x00">
        <name>PIR Occupied To Unoccupied Delay</name>
        <description>The PIROccupiedToUnoccupiedDelay attribute is 8-bits in length and specifies the time delay, in seconds, before the PIR sensor changes to its occupied state when the sensed area becomes unoccupied. This attribute, along with PIRUnoccupiedToOccupiedTime, may be used to reduce sensor &apos;chatter&apos; when used in an area where occupation changes frequently.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0011" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFFFE" default="0x00">
        <name>PIR Unoccupied To Occupied Delay</name>
        <description>The PIRUnoccupiedToOccupiedDelay attribute is 8-bits in length and specifies the time delay, in seconds, before the PIR sensor changes to its unoccupied state when the sensed area becomes occupied.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0012" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" minimum="0x01" maximum="0xFE" default="0x01">
        <name>PIR Unoccupied To Occupied Threshold</name>
        <description>The PIRUnoccupiedToOccupiedThreshold attribute is 8 bits in length and specifies the number of movement detection events that must occur in the period PIRUnoccupiedToOccupiedDelay, before the PIR sensor changes to its occupied state. This attribute is mandatory if the PIRUnoccupiedToOccupiedDelay attribute is implemented.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0020" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFFFE" default="0x00">
        <name>Ultra Sonic Occupied To Unoccupied Delay</name>
        <description>The UltraSonicOccupiedToUnoccupiedTime attribute specifies the time delay, in seconds, before the ultrasonic sensor changes to its occupied state when the sensed area becomes unoccupied. This attribute, along with UltraSonicUnoccupiedToOccupiedTime, may be used to reduce sensor &apos;chatter&apos; when used in an area where occupation changes frequently.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0021" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFFFE" default="0x00">
        <name>Ultra Sonic Unoccupied To Occupied Delay</name>
        <description>The UltraSonicUnoccupiedToOccupiedTime attribute specifies the time delay, in seconds, before the ultrasonic sensor changes to its unoccupied state when the sensed area becomes occupied.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0022" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="false" minimum="0x01" maximum="0xFE" default="0x01">
        <name>Ultrasonic Unoccupied To Occupied Threshold</name>
        <description>The UltrasonicUnoccupiedToOccupiedThreshold attribute is 8 bits in length and specifies the number of movement detection events that must occur in the period UltrasonicUnoccupiedToOccupiedDelay, before the Ultrasonic sensor changes to its occupied state. This attribute is mandatory if the UltrasonicUnoccupiedToOccupiedDelay attribute is implemented.</description>
    </attribute>

</cluster>
