<cluster xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="zigbee-description.xsd" code="0x0702">
    <name>Metering</name>
    <description>The Metering Cluster provides a mechanism to retrieve usage information from Electric, Gas, Water, and potentially Thermal metering devices. These devices can operate on either battery or mains power, and can have a wide variety of sophistication. The Metering Cluster is designed to provide flexibility while limiting capabilities to a set number of metered information types. More advanced forms or data sets from metering devices will be supported in the Smart Energy Tunneling Cluster</description>
    
    <command code="0x00" source="client">
        <name>Get Profile</name>
        <description>The GetProfile command is generated when a client device wishes to retrieve a list of captured Energy, Gas or water consumption for profiling purposes.</description>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="IntervalChannelEnum">
            <name>Interval Channel</name>
            <description>Enumerated value used to select the quantity of interest returned by the GetProfileReponse command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>End Time</name>
            <description>32-bit value (in UTCTime) used to select an Intervals block from all the Intervals blocks available. The Intervals block returned is the most recent block with its EndTime equal or older to the one provided. The most recent Intervals block is requested using an End Time set to 0x00000000, subsequent Intervals block are requested using an End time set to the EndTime of the previous block - (number of intervals of the previous block * ProfileIntervalPeriod).</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Number Of Periods</name>
            <description>Represents the number of intervals being requested. This value cannot exceed the size stipulated in the MaxNumberOfPeriodsDelivered attribute. If more intervals are requested than can be delivered, the GetProfileResponse will return the number of intervals equal to MaxNumberOfPeriodsDelivered. If fewer intervals are available for the time period, only those available are returned.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x01" source="client">
        <name>Request Mirror Response</name>
        <description>The Request Mirror Response Command allows the ESI to inform a sleepy Metering Device it has the ability to store and mirror its data.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Endpoint ID</name>
            <description>16 Bit Unsigned Integer indicating the End Point ID to contain the Metering Devices meter data. Valid End Point ID values are 0x0001 to 0x00F0. If the ESI is able to mirror the Metering Device data, the low byte of the unsigned 16 bit integer shall be used to contain the eight bit EndPoint ID. If the ESI is unable to mirror the Metering Device data, EndPoint ID shall be returned as 0xFFFF. All other EndPoint ID values are reserved. If valid, the Metering device shall use the EndPoint ID to forward its metered data.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x02" source="client">
        <name>Mirror Removed</name>
        <description>The Mirror Removed Command allows the ESI to inform a sleepy Metering Device mirroring support has been removed or halted.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Removed Endpoint ID</name>
            <description>16 Bit Unsigned Integer indicating the End Point ID previously containing the Metering Devices meter data.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x03" source="client">
        <name>Request Fast Poll Mode</name>
        <description>The Request Fast Poll Mode command is generated when the metering client wishes to receive near real-time updates of InstantaneousDemand.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Fast Poll Update Period</name>
            <description>Desired fast poll period not to be less than the FastPollUpdatePeriod attribute.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Duration</name>
            <description>Desired duration for the server to remain in fast poll mode not to exceed 15 minutes.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x04" source="client">
        <name>Schedule Snapshot</name>
        <description>This command is used to set up a schedule of when the device shall create snapshot data.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. When new information is provided that replaces older information for the same time period, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. The value contained in this field is a unique number managed by upstream servers or a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the snapshot command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.This is required when the snapshot data needs to be transmitted over several messages, allowing for the client to easily identify the set of messages that form a group.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Command Index</name>
            <description>The CommandIndex is used to count the payload fragments for the case where the entire payload does not fit into one message. The CommandIndex starts at 0 and is incremented for each fragment belonging to the same command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Total Number of Commands</name>
            <description>In the case where the entire payload does not fit into one message, the Total Number of Commands field indicates the total number of sub-commands in the message.</description>
        </field>
        <field class="SnapshotSchedulePayload">
            <name>Snapshot Schedule Payload</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x05" source="client">
        <name>Take Snapshot</name>
        <description>This command is used to instruct the cluster server to take a single snapshot.</description>
        <field type="BITMAP_32_BIT" class="SnapshotCauseBitmap">
            <name>Snapshot Cause</name>
            <description>A 32-bit BitMap indicating the cause of the snapshot. Note that the Manually Triggered from Client flag shall additionally be set for all Snapshots triggered in this manner.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x06" source="client">
        <name>Get Snapshot</name>
        <description>This command is used to request snapshot data from the cluster server.</description>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Earliest Start Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Timestamp indicating the earliest time of a snapshot to be returned by a corresponding Publish Snapshot command. Snapshots with a time stamp equal to or greater than the specified Earliest Start Time shall be returned.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Latest End Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Timestamp indicating the latest time of a snapshot to be returned by a corresponding Publish Snapshot command. Snapshots with a time stamp less than the specified Latest End Time shall be returned.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Snapshot Offset</name>
            <description>Where multiple snapshots satisfy the selection criteria specified by the other fields in this command, this field identifies the individual snapshot to be returned. An offset of zero (0x00) indicates that the first snapshot satisfying the selection criteria should be returned, 0x01 the second, and so on.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_32_BIT" class="SnapshotCauseBitmap">
            <name>Snapshot Cause</name>
            <description>This field is used to select only snapshots that were taken due to a specific cause. Setting this field to 0xFFFFFFFF indicates that all snapshots should be selected, irrespective of the cause.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x07" source="client">
        <name>Start Sampling</name>
        <description>The sampling mechanism allows a set of samples of the specified type of data to be taken, commencing at the stipulated start time. This mechanism may run concurrently with the capturing of profile data, and may refer the same parameters, albeit possibly at a different sampling rate.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. When new information is provided that replaces older information for the same time period, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. The value contained in this field is a unique number managed by upstream servers or a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information. Commands should be ignored if the value of the Issuer Event ID is equal to or less than the previous value; a device MAY return a ZCL Default Response command in this case.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Start Sampling Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Time field to denote the time at which the sampling should start. A start Date/Time of 0x00000000 shall indicate that the command should be executed immediately. A start Date/Time of 0xFFFFFFFF shall cause an existing StartSampling command with the same Issuer Event ID to be cancelled.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SampleTypeEnum">
            <name>Sample Type</name>
            <description>An 8 bit enumeration that identifies the type of data being sampled.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Sample Request Interval</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit field representing the interval or time in seconds between samples.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Max Number Of Samples</name>
            <description>A 16 bit unsigned integer that represents the number of samples to be taken.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x08" source="client">
        <name>Get Sampled Data</name>
        <description>This command is used to request sampled data from the server. Note that it is the responsibility of the client to ensure that it does not request more samples than can be held in a single command payload.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Sample ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier allocated to this Sampling session. This field allows devices to match response data with the appropriate request.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Earliest Sample Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Timestamp indicating the earliest time of a sample to be returned. Samples with a timestamp equal to or greater than the specified EarliestSampleTime shall be returned.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SampleTypeEnum">
            <name>Sample Type</name>
            <description>An 8 bit enumeration that identifies the required type of sampled data.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Number Of Samples</name>
            <description>Represents the number of samples being requested, This value cannot exceed the size stipulated in the MaxNumberofSamples field in the StartSampling command. If more samples are requested than can be delivered, the GetSampledDataResponse command will return the number of samples equal to the MaxNumberofSamples field. If fewer samples are available for the time period, only those available are returned.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x09" source="client">
        <name>Mirror Report Attribute Response</name>
        <description>FIXME: This command is sent in response to the ReportAttribute command when the MirrorReporting attribute is set.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Notification Scheme</name>
            <description>An unsigned 8-bit integer that allows for the pre-loading of the Notification Flags bit mapping to ZCL or Smart Energy Standard commands.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_32_BIT">
            <name>Notification Flags</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0A" source="client">
        <name>Reset Load Limit Counter</name>
        <description>The ResetLoadLimitCounter command shall cause the LoadLimitCounter attribute to be reset.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Provider ID</name>
            <description>An unsigned 32-bit field containing a unique identifier for the commodity provider.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. This field allows devices to determine if a new command has been issued. The value contained in this field is a unique number managed by upstream servers or a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, a newer command will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than previous versions of the command.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0B" source="client">
        <name>Change Supply</name>
        <description>This command is sent from the Head-end or ESI to the Metering Device to instruct it to change the status of the valve or load switch, i.e. the supply.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Provider ID</name>
            <description>An unsigned 32-bit field containing a unique identifier for the commodity provider to whom this command relates.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. When new information is provided that replaces older information for the same time period, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. The value contained in this field is a unique number managed by upstream servers or a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Request Date Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Time field to indicate the date and time at which the supply change was requested.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Implementation Date Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Time field to indicate the date at which the supply change is to be applied. An Implementation Date/Time of 0x00000000 shall indicate that the command should be executed immediately. An Implementation Date/Time of 0xFFFFFFFF shall cause an existing but pending Change Supply command with the same Provider ID and Issuer Event ID to be cancelled (the status of the supply will not change but the Proposed Change Supply Implementation Time attribute shall be reset to zero).</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="MeteringSupplyStatusEnum">
            <name>Proposed Supply Status</name>
            <description>An 8-bit enumeration field indicating the status of the energy supply controlled by the Metering Device following implementation of this command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_8_BIT" class="SupplyControlBitsBitmap">
            <name>Supply Control Bits</name>
            <description>An 8-bit BitMap where the least significant nibble defines the Supply Control bits.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0C" source="client">
        <name>Local Change Supply</name>
        <description>This command is a simplified version of the ChangeSupply command, intended to be sent from an IHD to a meter as the consequence of a user action on the IHD. Its purpose is to provide a local disconnection/reconnection button on the IHD in addition to the one on the meter.</description>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="ProposedSupplyStatusEnum">
            <name>Proposed Supply Status</name>
            <description>An 8-bit enumeration field indicating the status of the energy supply controlled by the Metering Device following implementation of this command.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0D" source="client">
        <name>Set Supply Status</name>
        <description>This command is used to specify the required status of the supply following the occurance of certain events on the meter.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. When new information is provided that replaces older information for the same time period, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. The value contained in this field is a unique number managed by upstream servers or a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SupplyStatusEnum">
            <name>Supply Tamper State</name>
            <description>The SupplyTamperState indicates the required status of the supply following the detection of a tamper event within the metering device.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SupplyStatusEnum">
            <name>Supply Depletion State</name>
            <description>The SupplyDepletionState indicates the required status of the supply following detection of a depleted battery within the metering device.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SupplyStatusEnum">
            <name>Supply Uncontrolled Flow State</name>
            <description>The SupplyUncontrolledFlowState indicates the required status of the supply following detection of an uncontrolled flow event within the metering device.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SupplyStatusEnum">
            <name>Load Limit Supply State</name>
            <description>The LoadLimitSupplyState indicates the required status of the supply once the device is in a load limit state.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0E" source="client">
        <name>Set Uncontrolled Flow Threshold</name>
        <description>This command is used to update the &apos;Uncontrolled Flow Rate&apos; configuration data used by flow meters.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Provider ID</name>
            <description>An unsigned 32-bit field containing a unique identifier for the commodity provider to whom this command relates.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. When new information is provided that replaces older information for the same time period, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. The value contained in this field is a unique number managed by upstream servers or a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Uncontrolled Flow Threshold</name>
            <description>The threshold above which a flow meter (e.g. Gas or Water) shall detect an uncontrolled flow. A value of 0x0000 indicates the feature in unused.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="UnitOfMeasureEnum">
            <name>Unit Of Measure</name>
            <description>An enumeration indicating the unit of measure to be used in conjunction with the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold attribute. The enumeration used for this field shall match one of the UnitOfMeasure values using a pure binary format as defined in the Metering cluster.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Multiplier</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit value indicating the multiplier, to be used in conjunction with the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold and Divisor fields, to determine the true flow threshold value. A value of 0x0000 is not allowed.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Divisor</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit value indicating the divisor, to be used in conjunction with the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold and Multiplier fields, to determine the true flow threshold value. A value of 0x0000 is not allowed.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Stabilisation Period</name>
            <description>An unsigned 8-bit value indicating the time given to allow the flow to stabilize. It is defined in units of tenths of a second.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Measurement Period</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit value indicating the period over which the flow is measured and compared against the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold value. It is defined in units of 1 second.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    
    <command code="0x00" source="server">
        <name>Get Profile Response</name>
        <description>This command is sent when the Client command GetProfile is received.</description>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>End Time</name>
            <description>32-bit value (in UTC) representing the end time of the most chronologically recent interval being requested. Example: Data collected from 2:00 PM to 3:00 PM would be specified as a 3:00 PM interval (end time). It is important to note that the current interval accumulating is not included in most recent block but can be retrieved using the CurrentPartialProfileIntervalValue attribute.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="GetProfileStatusEnum">
            <name>Status</name>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="IntervalPeriodEnum">
            <name>Profile Interval Period</name>
            <description>Represents the interval or time frame used to capture metered Energy, Gas, and Water consumption for profiling purposes.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Number Of Periods Delivered</name>
            <description>Represents the number of intervals the device is returning. Please note the number of periods returned in the Get Profile Response command can be calculated when the packets are received and can replace the usage of this field. The intent is to provide this information as a convenience.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Intervals</name>
            <description>Series of interval data captured using the period specified by the ProfileIntervalPeriod field. The content of the interval data depends of the type of information requested using the Channel field in the Get Profile Command, and will represent the change in that information since the previous interval. Data is organized in a reverse chronological order, the most recent interval is transmitted first and the oldest interval is transmitted last. Invalid intervals should be marked as 0xFFFFFF.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x01" source="server">
        <name>Request Mirror</name>
        <description>This command is used to request the ESI to mirror Metering Device data.</description>
    </command>
    <command code="0x02" source="server">
        <name>Remove Mirror</name>
        <description>This command is used to request the ESI to remove its mirror of Metering Device data.</description>
    </command>
    <command code="0x03" source="server">
        <name>Request Fast Poll Mode Response</name>
        <description>This command is generated when the client command Request Fast Poll Mode is received.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Applied Update Period</name>
            <description>The period at which metering data shall be updated. This may be different than the requested fast poll. If the Request Fast Poll Rate is less than Fast Poll Update Period Attribute, it shall use the Fast Poll Update Period Attribute. Otherwise, the Applied Update Period shall be greater than or equal to the minimum Fast Poll Update Period Attribute and less than or equal to the Requested Fast Poll Rate.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Fast Poll Mode Endtime</name>
            <description>UTC time that indicates when the metering server will terminate fast poll mode and resume updating at the rate specified by DefaultUpdatePeriod. For example, one or more metering clients may request fast poll mode while the metering server is already in fast poll mode. The intent is that the fast poll mode will not be extended since this scenario would make it possible to be in fast poll mode longer than 15 minutes.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x04" source="server">
        <name>Schedule Snapshot Response</name>
        <description>This command is generated in response to a ScheduleSnapshot command, and is sent to confirm whether the requested snapshot schedule has been set up.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. The value contained in this field indicates the value allocated to the ScheduleSnapshot command for which this response is generated.</description>
        </field>
        <field class="SnapshotResponsePayload">
            <name>Snapshot Response Payload</name>
            <description>The ScheduleSnapshotResponse payload may contain several instances of the sub-payload. Each instance is an acknowledgment from the device for a scheduled snapshot and the ability for the device to support that type of snapshot.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x05" source="server">
        <name>Take Snapshot Response</name>
        <description>This command is generated in response to a TakeSnapshot command, and is sent to confirm whether the requested snapshot has been accepted and successfully taken.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Snapshot ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier allocated by the device creating the snapshot. The value contained in this field indicates the TakeSnapshot command for which this response is generated.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SnapshotConfirmationEnum">
            <name>Snapshot Confirmation</name>
            <description>This is the acknowledgment from the device that it can support this required type of snapshot.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x06" source="server">
        <name>Publish Snapshot</name>
        <description>This command is generated in response to a GetSnapshot command. It is used to return a single snapshot to the client.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Snapshot ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier allocated by the device creating the snapshot.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Snapshot Time</name>
            <description>This is a 32 bit value (in UTC Time) representing the time at which the data snapshot was taken.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Total Snapshots Found</name>
            <description>An 8-bit Integer indicating the number of snapshots found, based on the search criteria defined in the associated GetSnapshot command. If the value is greater than 1, the client is able to request the next snapshot by incrementing the Snapshot Offset field in an otherwise repeated GetSnapshot command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Command Index</name>
            <description>The CommandIndex is used to count the payload fragments in the case where the entire payload (snapshot) does not fit into one message. The CommandIndex starts at 0 and is incremented for each fragment belonging to the same command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Total Number Of Commands</name>
            <description>In the case where the entire payload (snapshot) does not fit into one message, the Total Number of Commands field indicates the total number of sub-commands that will be returned.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_32_BIT" class="SnapshotCauseBitmap">
            <name>Snapshot Cause</name>
            <description>A 32-bit BitMap indicating the cause of the snapshot.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SnapshotPayloadTypeEnum">
            <name>Snapshot Payload Type</name>
            <description>The SnapshotPayloadType is an 8-bit enumerator defining the format of the SnapshotSubPayload in this message. The server selects the SnapshotPayloadType based on the charging scheme in use.</description>
            <description>If the snapshot is taken by the server due to a change of Tariff Information (cause = 3) which involves a change in charging scheme then two snapshots shall be taken, the first according to the charging scheme being dismissed, the second to the scheme being introduced.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Snapshot Payload</name>
            <description>The format of the SnapshotSub-Payload differs depending on the SnapshotPayloadType, as shown below. Note that, where the entire payload (snapshot) does not fit into one message, only the leading (non-Sub-Payload) fields of the Snapshot payload are repeated in each command; the SnapshotSub-Payload is divided over the required number of commands.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x07" source="server">
        <name>Get Sampled Data Response</name>
        <description>FIXME: This command is used to send the requested sample data to the client. It is generated in response to a GetSampledData command.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Sample ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier allocated to this Sampling session. This field allows devices to match response data with the appropriate request.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Sample Start Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Time field to denote the time of the first sample returned in this response.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SampleTypeEnum">
            <name>Sample Type</name>
            <description>An 8 bit enumeration that identifies the type of data being sampled.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Sample Request Interval</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit field representing the interval or time in seconds between samples.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Number Of Samples</name>
            <description>Represents the number of samples being requested, This value cannot exceed the size stipulated in the MaxNumberofSamples field in the StartSampling command. If more samples are requested than can be delivered, the GetSampleDataResponse command will return the number of samples equal to MaxNumberofSamples field. If fewer samples are available for the time period, only those available shall be returned.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Samples</name>
            <description>Series of data samples captured using the interval specified by the SampleRequestInterval field in the StartSampling command. Each sample contains the change in the relevant data since the previous sample. Data is organised in a chronological order, the oldest sample is transmitted first and the most recent sample is transmitted last. Invalid samples should be marked as 0xFFFFFF.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x08" source="server">
        <name>Configure Mirror</name>
        <description>FIXME: ConfigureMirror is sent to the mirror once the mirror has been created. The command deals with the operational configuration of the Mirror.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the device being mirrored. When new information is provided that replaces older information, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. It is recommended that the value contained in this field is a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Reporting Interval</name>
            <description>An unsigned 24-bit integer to denote the interval, in seconds, at which a mirrored meter intends to use the ReportAttribute command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="BOOLEAN">
            <name>Mirror Notification Reporting</name>
            <description>A Boolean used to advise a BOMD how the Notification flags should be acquired (see below).</description>
            <description>When Mirror Notification Reporting is set, the MirrorReportAttributeResponse command is enabled. In that case, the Metering client on the mirror endpoint shall respond to the last or only ReportAttribute command with the MirrorReportAttributeResponse.</description>
            <description>If Mirror Notification Reporting is set to FALSE, the MirrorReportAttributeResponse command shall not be enabled; the Metering server may poll the Notification flags by means of a normal ReadAttribute command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Notification Scheme</name>
            <description>This unsigned 8-bit integer allows for the pre-loading of the Notification Flags bit mapping to ZCL or Smart Energy Standard commands.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x09" source="server">
        <name>Configure Notification Scheme</name>
        <description>FIXME: The ConfigureNotificationScheme is sent to the mirror once the mirror has been created. The command deals with the operational configuration of the Mirror and the device that reports to the mirror. No default schemes are allowed to be overwritten.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the device being mirrored. When new information is provided that replaces older information, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. It is recommended that the value contained in this field is a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Notification Scheme</name>
            <description>An unsigned 8-bit integer that allows for the pre-loading of the Notification Flags bit mapping to ZCL or Smart Energy Standard commands.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_32_BIT">
            <name>Notification Flag Order</name>
            <description>A 32-bit bitmap, consisting of 8 nibbles which define the Notification Flag attributes (and order) to be returned in a MirrorReportAttributeResponse command.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0A" source="server">
        <name>Configure Notification Flags</name>
        <description>The ConfigureNotificationFlags command is used to set the commands relating to the bit value for each NotificationFlags attribute that the scheme is proposing to use.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the device being mirrored. When new information is provided that replaces older information, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. It is recommended that the value contained in this field is a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Notification Scheme</name>
            <description>An unsigned 8-bit integer that allows for the pre-loading of the Notification Flags bit mapping to ZCL or Smart Energy Standard commands.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Notification Flag Attribute ID</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit integer that denotes the attribute id of the Notification flag (2-8) that will be configured for this Notification scheme.</description>
        </field>
        <field class="NotificationCommandSubPayload">
            <name>Sub Payload</name>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0B" source="server">
        <name>Get Notified Message</name>
        <description>The GetNotifiedMessage command is used only when a BOMD is being mirrored. This command provides a method for the BOMD to notify the Mirror message queue that it wants to receive commands that the Mirror has queued. The Notification flags set within the command shall inform the mirror of the commands that the BOMD is requesting.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Notification Scheme</name>
            <description>An unsigned 8-bit integer that allows for the pre-loading of the Notification Flags bit mapping to ZCL or Smart Energy Standard commands.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Notification Flag Attribute ID</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit integer that denotes the attribute id of the notification flag (1-8) that is included in this command.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_32_BIT">
            <name>Notification Flags N</name>
            <description>The Notification Flags attribute/parameter indicating the command being requested.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0C" source="server">
        <name>Supply Status Response</name>
        <description>This command is transmitted by a Metering Device in response to a ChangeSupply command.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Provider ID</name>
            <description>An unsigned 32-bit field containing a unique identifier for the commodity provider to whom this command relates.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Issuer Event ID</name>
            <description>Unique identifier generated by the commodity provider. When new information is provided that replaces older information for the same time period, this field allows devices to determine which information is newer. The value contained in this field is a unique number managed by upstream servers or a UTC based time stamp (UTCTime data type) identifying when the command was issued. Thus, newer information will have a value in the Issuer Event ID field that is larger than older information.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Implementation Date Time</name>
            <description>A UTC Time field to indicate the date at which the originating command was to be applied.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="MeteringSupplyStatusEnum">
            <name>Supply Status</name>
            <description>An 8-bit enumeration field indicating the status of the energy supply controlled by the Metering Device following implementation of the originating command.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    <command code="0x0D" source="server">
        <name>Start Sampling Response</name>
        <description>This command is transmitted by a Metering Device in response to a StartSampling command.</description>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Sample ID</name>
            <description>16 Bit Unsigned Integer indicating the ID allocated by the Metering Device for the requested Sampling session. If the Metering Device is unable to support a further Sampling session, Sample ID shall be returned as 0xFFFF. If valid, the Sample ID shall be used for all further communication regarding this Sampling session.</description>
            <description>NOTE that the Metering Device may reserve a Sample ID of 0x0000 in order to provide an alternative mechanism for retrieving Profile data. This mechanism will allow an increased number of samples to be returned than is available via the existing (automatically started) Profile mechanism.</description>
        </field>
    </command>
    
    <attribute code="0x0000" type="BITMAP_32_BIT" side="client" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00000000">
        <name>Functional Notification Flags</name>
        <description>The FunctionalNotificationFlags attribute is implemented as a set of bit flags which are have a predefined action associated with a bit that is not based on a specific command, but may require the Mirrored device to trigger some additional functionality within the system.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0001"  arraystart="2" arraycount="7" type="BITMAP_32_BIT" side="client" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00000000">
        <name>Notification Flags {{count}}</name>
        <description>NotificationFlags2 to NotificationFlags8 are 32-bit bitmaps that each represent a series of flags. Each flag represents an outstanding command that the Mirror is holding on behalf of the BOMD. Each flag represents a different command. The format of these attributes is dictated by the scheme that is currently in operation.</description>
    </attribute>

    <attribute code="0x0000" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Summation Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentSummationDelivered represents the most recent summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered and consumed in the premises. CurrentSummationDelivered is mandatory and must be provided as part of the minimum data set to be provided by the metering device. CurrentSummationDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0001" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Summation Received</name>
        <description>CurrentSummationReceived represents the most recent summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water generated and delivered from the premises. If optionally provided, CurrentSummationReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0002" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Max Demand Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentMaxDemandDelivered represents the maximum demand or rate of delivered value of Energy, Gas, or Water being utilized at the premises. If optionally provided, CurrentMaxDemandDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0003" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Max Demand Received</name>
        <description>CurrentMaxDemandReceived represents the maximum demand or rate of received value of Energy, Gas, or Water being utilized by the utility. If optionally provided, CurrentMaxDemandReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0004" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Dft Summation</name>
        <description>DFTSummation represents a snapshot of attribute CurrentSummationDelivered captured at the time indicated by attribute DailyFreezeTime. If optionally provided, DFTSummation is updated once every 24 hours.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0005" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0x173B" default="0x0000">
        <name>Daily Freeze Time</name>
        <description>DailyFreezeTime represents the time of day when DFTSummation is captured. DailyFreezeTime is an unsigned 16-bit value representing the hour and minutes for DFT.</description>
        <description>Bits 0 to 7: Range of 0 to 0x3B representing the number of minutes past the top of the hour.</description>
        <description>Bits 8 to 15: Range of 0 to 0x17 representing the hour of the day (in 24-hour format). Note that midnight shall be represented as 00:00 only.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0006" type="SIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x-64" maximum="0x64" default="0x00">
        <name>Power Factor</name>
        <description>PowerFactor contains the Average Power Factor ratio in 1/100ths. Valid values are 0 to 99.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0007" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Reading Snapshot Time</name>
        <description>The ReadingSnapshotTime attribute represents the last time all of the CurrentSummationDelivered, CurrentSummationReceived, CurrentMaxDemandDelivered, and CurrentMaxDemandReceived attributes that are supported by the device were updated.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0008" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Max Demand Delivered Time</name>
        <description>The CurrentMaxDemandDeliveredTime attribute represents the time when CurrentMaxDemandDelivered reading was captured.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0009" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Max Demand Received Time</name>
        <description>The CurrentMaxDemandReceivedTime attribute represents the time when CurrentMaxDemandReceived reading was captured.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x000A" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x1E">
        <name>Default Update Period</name>
        <description>The DefaultUpdatePeriod attribute represents the interval (seconds) at which the InstantaneousDemand attribute is updated when not in fast poll mode. InstantaneousDemand may be continuously updated as new measurements are acquired, but at a minimum InstantaneousDemand must be updated at the DefaultUpdatePeriod. The DefaultUpdatePeriod may apply to other attributes as defined by the device manufacturer.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x000B" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x05">
        <name>Fast Poll Update Period</name>
        <description>The FastPollUpdatePeriod attribute represents the interval (seconds) at which the InstantaneousDemandattribute is updated when in fast poll mode. InstantaneousDemand may be continuously updated as new measurements are acquired, but at a minimum, InstantaneousDemand must be updated at the FastPollUpdatePeriod. The FastPollUpdatePeriod may apply to other attributes as defined by the device manufacturer.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x000C" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Block Period Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>The CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered attribute represents the most recent summed value of Energy, Gas or Water delivered and consumed in the premises during the Block Tariff Period.</description>
        <description>The CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered is reset at the start of each Block Tariff Period.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x000D" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Daily Consumption Target</name>
        <description>The DailyConsumptionTarget attribute is a daily target consumption amount that can be displayed to the consumer on a HAN device, with the intent that it can be used to compare to actual daily consumption (e.g. compare to the CurrentDayConsumptionDelivered).</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x000E" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Block</name>
        <description>When Block Tariffs are enabled, CurrentBlock is an 8-bit Enumeration which indicates the currently active block. If blocks are active then the current active block is based on the CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered and the block thresholds. Block 1 is active when the value of CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered is less than or equal to the Block1Threshold value, Block 2 is active when CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered is greater than Block1Threshold value and less than or equal to the8 Block2Threshold value, and so on. Block 16 is active when the value of CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered is greater than Block15Threshold value.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x000F" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Profile Interval Period</name>
        <description>The ProfileIntervalPeriod attribute is currently included in the Get Profile Response command payload, but does not appear in an attribute set. This represents the duration of each interval. ProfileIntervalPeriod represents the interval or time frame used to capture metered Energy, Gas, and Water consumption for profiling purposes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0010" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF" default="0x0000">
        <name>Interval Read Reporting Period</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0011" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0x173B" default="0x0000">
        <name>Preset Reading Time</name>
        <description>The PresetReadingTime attribute represents the time of day (in quarter hour increments) at which the meter will wake up and report a register reading even if there has been no consumption for the previous 24 hours. PresetReadingTime is an unsigned 16-bit value representing the hour and minutes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0012" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF">
        <name>Volume Per Report</name>
        <description>The VolumePerReport attribute represents the volume per report increment from the water or gas meter. For example a gas meter might be set to report its register reading for every time 1 cubic meter of gas is used. For a water meter it might report the register value every 10 liters of water usage.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0013" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF">
        <name>Flow Restriction</name>
        <description>The FlowRestriction attribute represents the volume per minute limit set in the flow restrictor. This applies to water but not for gas. A setting of 0xFF indicates this feature is disabled.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0014" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SupplyStatusEnum" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Supply Status</name>
        <description>The SupplyStatus attribute represents the state of the supply at the customer's premises.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0015" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Inlet Energy Carrier Summation</name>
        <description>CurrentInletEnergyCarrierSummation is the current integrated volume of a given energy carrier measured on the inlet. The formatting and unit of measure for this value is specified in the EnergyCarrierUnitOfMeasure and EnergyCarrierSummationFormatting attributes</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0016" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Outlet Energy Carrier Summation</name>
        <description>CurrentOutletEnergyCarrierSummation is the current integrated volume of a given energy carrier measured on the outlet. The formatting and unit of measure for this value is specified in the EnergyCarrierUnitOfMeasure and EnergyCarrierSummationFormatting attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0017" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Inlet Temperature</name>
        <description>InletTemperature is the temperature measured on the energy carrier inlet.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0018" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Outlet Temperature</name>
        <description>OutletTemperature is the temperature measured on the energy carrier outlet.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0019" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Control Temperature</name>
        <description>ControlTemperature is a reference temperature measured on the meter used to validate the Inlet/Outlet temperatures.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x001A" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Inlet Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentInletEnergyCarrierDemand is the current absolute demand on the energy carrier inlet.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x001B" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Outlet Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentOutletEnergyCarrierDemand is the current absolute demand on the energy carrier outlet.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x001C" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Block Period Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>The PreviousBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered attribute represents the total value of Energy, Gas or Water delivered and consumed in the premises at the end of the previous Block Tariff Period. If supported, the PreviousBlockPeriodConsumptionDelivered attribute is updated at the end of each Block Tariff Period.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x001D" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Block Period Consumption Received</name>
        <description>The CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionReceived attribute represents the most recent summed value of Energy, Gas or Water received by the energy supplier from the premises during the Block Tariff Period. The CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionReceived attribute is reset at the start of each Block Tariff Period.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x001E" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Block Received</name>
        <description>When Block Tariffs are enabled, CurrentBlockReceived is an 8-bit Enumeration which indicates the currently active block. If blocks are active then the current active block is based on the CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionReceived and the block thresholds. Block 1 is active when the value of CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionReceived is less than or equal to the Block1Threshold value, Block 2 is active when CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionReceived is greater than Block1Threshold value and less than or equal to the Block2Threshold value, and so on. Block 16 is active when the value of CurrentBlockPeriodConsumptionReceived is greater than Block15Threshold value.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x001F" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Dft Summation Received</name>
        <description>DFTSummationReceived represents a snapshot of attribute CurrentSummationReceived captured at the time indicated by the DailyFreezeTime attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0020" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Active Register Tier Delivered</name>
        <description>The ActiveRegisterTierDelivered attribute indicates the current register tier that the energy consumed is being accumulated against.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0021" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Active Register Tier Received</name>
        <description>The ActiveRegisterTierReceived attribute indicates the current register tier that the energy generated is being accumulated against.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0022" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="true" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Last Block Switch Time</name>
        <description>This attribute allows other devices to determine the time at which a meter switches from one block to another.</description>
        <description>When Block Tariffs are enabled, the LastBlockSwitchTime attribute represents the timestamp of the last update to the CurrentBlock attribute, as a result of the consumption exceeding a threshold, or the start of a new block period and/or billing period.</description>
        <description>If, at the start of a new block period and/or billing period, the value of the CurrentBlock attribute is still set to Block1 (0x01), the CurrentBlock attribute value will not change but the LastBlockSwitchTime attribute shall be updated to indicate this change.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0100" arraystart="1" arraycount="48" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
        <description>Attributes CurrentTier1SummationDelivered through CurrentTierNSummationDelivered represent the most recent summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises (i.e. delivered to the customer from the utility) at a specific price tier as defined by a TOU schedule or a real time pricing period. If optionally provided, attributes CurrentTier1SummationDelivered through CurrentTierNSummationDelivered are updated continuously as new measurements are made.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0101" arraystart="1" arraycount="48" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>

    <attribute code="0x01FC" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>CPP 1 Summation Delivered</name>
        <description>CPP1SummationDelivered represents the most recent summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises (i.e. delivered to the customer from the utility) while Critical Peak Price CPP1 was being applied. If optionally provided, attribute CPP1SummationDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x01FE" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>CPP 2 Summation Delivered</name>
        <description>CPP2SummationDelivered represents the most recent summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises (i.e. delivered to the customer from the utility) while Critical Peak Price CPP2 was being applied. If optionally provided, attribute CPP2SummationDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0200" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>Status</name>
        <description>The Status attribute provides indicators reflecting the current error conditions found by the metering device. This attribute is an 8-bit field where when an individual bit is set, an error or warning condition exists. The behavior causing the setting or resetting each bit is device specific. In other words, the application within the metering device will determine and control when these settings are either set or cleared.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0201" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF">
        <name>Remaining Battery Life</name>
        <description>RemainingBatteryLife represents the estimated remaining life of the battery in % of capacity. A setting of 0xFF indicates this feature is disabled. The range 0 - 100 where 100 = 100%, 0xFF = Unknown.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0202" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Hours In Operation</name>
        <description>HoursInOperation is a counter that increments once every hour during operation. This may be used as a check for tampering.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0203" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Hours In Fault</name>
        <description>HoursInFault is a counter that increments once every hour when the device is in operation with a fault detected. This may be used as a check for tampering.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0204" type="BITMAP_64_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Extended Status</name>
        <description>The ExtendedStatus attribute reflects the state of items in a meter that the standard Status attribute cannot show. The Extended Status BitMap is split into two groups of flags: general flags and metering type specific flags. Flags are currently defined for electricity and gas meters; flag definitions for other commodities will be added as and when their usage is agreed.</description>
        <description>These flags are set and reset by the meter autonomously; they cannot be reset by other devices.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0205" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF">
        <name>Remaining Battery Life In Days</name>
        <description>RemainingBatteryLifeInDays attribute represents the estimated remaining life of the battery in days of capacity. The range is 0  0xFFFE, where 0xFFFF represents 'Invalid', 'Unused' and 'Disabled'.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0206" type="OCTET_STRING" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Meter ID</name>
        <description>CurrentMeterID attribute is the current id for the Meter. This could be the current firmware version supported on the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0207" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Ambient Consumption Indicator</name>
        <description>The AmbientConsumptionIndicator attribute is an 8-bit enumeration which provides a simple (i.e. Low/Medium/High) indication of the amount of a commodity being consumed within the premises. The status is achieved by comparing the current value of the InstantaneousDemand attribute with low/medium and medium/high thresholds.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0300" class="UnitOfMeasure" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>Unit Of Measure</name>
        <description>UnitofMeasure provides a label for the Energy, Gas, or Water being measured by the metering device. The unit of measure applies to all summations, consumptions/ profile interval and demand/rate supported by this cluster other than those specifically identified as being based upon the EnergyCarrierUnitOfMeasure or the AlternativeUnitofMeasure. Other measurements such as the power factor are self describing.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0301" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Multiplier</name>
        <description>Multiplier provides a value to be multiplied against a raw or uncompensated sensor count of Energy, Gas, or Water being measured by the metering device. If present, this attribute must be applied against all summation, consumption and demand values to derive the delivered and received values expressed in the unit of measure specified. This attribute must be used in conjunction with the Divisor attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0302" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Divisor</name>
        <description>Divisor provides a value to divide the results of applying the Multiplier Attribute against a raw or uncompensated sensor count of Energy, Gas, or Water being measured by the metering device. If present, this attribute must be applied against all summation, consumption and demand values to derive the delivered and received values expressed in the unit of measure specified. This attribute must be used in conjunction with the Multiplier attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0303" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Summation Formatting</name>
        <description>SummationFormatting provides a method to properly decipher the number of digits and the decimal location of the values found in the Summation Information Set of attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0304" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Demand Formatting</name>
        <description>DemandFormatting provides a method to properly decipher the number of digits and the decimal location of the values found in the Demand-related attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0305" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Historical Consumption Formatting</name>
        <description>HistoricalConsumptionFormatting provides a method to properly decipher the number of digits and the decimal location of the values found in the Historical Consumption Set of attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0306" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" class="MeteringDeviceTypeEnum" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Metering Device Type</name>
        <description>MeteringDeviceType provides a label for identifying the type of metering device present. The attribute are values representing Energy, Gas, Water, Thermal, Heat, Cooling, and mirrored metering devices.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0307" type="OCTET_STRING" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Site ID</name>
        <description>The SiteID is a ZCL Octet String field capable of storing a 32 character string (the first Octet indicates length) encoded in UTF-8 format. The SiteID is a text string, known in the UK as the MPAN number for electricity, MPRN for gas and 'Stand Point' in South Africa. These numbers specify the meter point location in a standardized way. The field is defined to accommodate the number of characters typically found in the UK and Europe (16 digits). Generally speaking the field is numeric but is defined for the possibility of an alpha-numeric format by specifying an octet string.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0308" type="OCTET_STRING" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Meter Serial Number</name>
        <description>The MeterSerialNumber is a ZCL Octet String field capable of storing a 24 character string (the first Octet indicates length) encoded in UTF-8 format. It is used to provide a unique identification of the metering device.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0309" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="UnitofMeasure" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Energy Carrier Unit Of Measure</name>
        <description>The EnergyCarrierUnitOfMeasure specifies the unit of measure that the EnergyCarrier is measured in. This unit of measure is typically a unit of volume or flow and cannot be an amount of energy.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x030A" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Energy Carrier Summation Formatting</name>
        <description>EnergyCarrierSummationFormatting provides a method to properly decipher the number of digits and the decimal location of the values found in the Summation- related attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x030B" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Energy Carrier Demand Formatting</name>
        <description>EnergyCarrierDemandFormatting provides a method to properly decipher the number of digits and the decimal location of the values found in the Demand-related attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x030C" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="TemperatureUnitOfMeasureEnum" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Temperature Unit Of Measure</name>
        <description>TemperatureFormatting provides a method to properly decipher the number of digits and the decimal location of the values found in the Temperature-related attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x030D" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Temperature Formatting</name>
        <description>The TemperatureUnitOfMeasure specifies the unit of measure that temperatures are measured in.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x030E" type="OCTET_STRING" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Module Serial Number</name>
        <description>The ModuleSerialNumber attribute represents the serial number (unique identifier) of the meter module. It is a ZCL Octet String field capable of storing a 24 character string (the first Octet indicates length) encoded in UTF-8 format. It shall be used to uniquely identify the meter communications module.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x030F" type="OCTET_STRING" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Operating Tariff Label Delivered</name>
        <description>The OperatingTariffLabelDelivered attribute is the meters version of the TariffLabel attribute that is found within the Tariff Information attribute set of the Price Cluster. It is used to identify the current consumption tariff operating on the meter. The attribute is a ZCL Octet String field capable of storing a 24 character string (the first Octet indicates length) encoded in UTF-8 format.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0310" type="OCTET_STRING" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Operating Tariff Label Received</name>
        <description>The OperatingTariffLabelReceived attribute is the meters version of the ReceivedTariffLabel attribute that is found within the Tariff Information attribute set of the Price Cluster. It is used to identify the current generation tariff operating on the meter. The attribute is a ZCL Octet String field capable of storing a 24 character string (the first Octet indicates length) encoded in UTF-8 format.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0311" type="OCTET_STRING" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Customer ID Number</name>
        <description>The CustomerIDNumber attribute provides a customer identification which may be used to confirm the customer at the premises. The attribute is a ZCL Octet String field capable of storing a 24 character string (not including the first Octet which indicates length) encoded in UTF-8 format.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0312" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>Alternative Unit Of Measure</name>
        <description>Unless stated otherwise, the AlternativeUnitofMeasure attribute provides a base for the attributes in the Alternative Historical Consumption attribute set.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0313" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Alternative Demand Formatting</name>
        <description>AlternativeDemandFormatting provides a method to properly decipher the number of digits and the decimal location of the values found in the Alternative Demand-related attributes.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0314" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Alternative Consumption Formatting</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0400" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x000000">
        <name>Instantaneous Demand</name>
        <description>InstantaneousDemand represents the current Demand of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered or received at the premises. Positive values indicate demand delivered to the premises where negative values indicate demand received from the premises. InstantaneousDemand is updated continuously as new measurements are made. The frequency of updates to this field is specific to the metering device, but should be within the range of once every second to once every 5 seconds.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0401" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentDayConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, CurrentDayConsumptionDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0402" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Consumption Received</name>
        <description>CurrentDayConsumptionReceived represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water received from the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, CurrentDayConsumptionReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0403" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>PreviousDayConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, PreviousDayConsumptionDelivered is updated every HFT. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0404" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Consumption Received</name>
        <description>PreviousDayConsumptionReceived represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water received from the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, PreviousDayConsumptionReceived is updated every HFT. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0405" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Partial Profile Interval Start Time Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentPartialProfileIntervalStartTimeDelivered represents the start time of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity delivered.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0406" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Partial Profile Interval Start Time Received</name>
        <description>CurrentPartialProfileIntervalStartTimeReceived represents the start time of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity received.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0407" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Partial Profile Interval Value Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentPartialProfileIntervalValueDelivered represents the value of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity delivered.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0408" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Partial Profile Interval Value Received</name>
        <description>CurrentPartialProfileIntervalValueReceived represents the value of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity received.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0409" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Max Pressure</name>
        <description>CurrentDayMaxPressure is the maximum pressure reported during a day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x040A" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Min Pressure</name>
        <description>CurrentDayMinPressure is the minimum pressure reported during a day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x040B" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Max Pressure</name>
        <description>PreviousDayMaxPressure represents the maximum pressure reported during previous day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x040C" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Min Pressure</name>
        <description>PreviousDayMinPressure represents the minimum pressure reported during previous day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x040D" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Max Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentDayMaxDemand represents the maximum demand or rate of delivered value of Energy, Gas, or Water being utilized at the premises.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x040E" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Max Demand</name>
        <description>PreviousDayMaxDemand represents the maximum demand or rate of delivered value of Energy, Gas, or Water being utilized at the premises.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x040F" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Month Max Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthMaxDemand is the maximum demand reported during a month from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0410" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Year Max Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentYearMaxDemand is the maximum demand reported during a year from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0411" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Max Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentDayMaxEnergyCarrierDemand is the maximum energy carrier demand reported during a day from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0412" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Max Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>PreviousDayMaxEnergyCarrierDemand is the maximum energy carrier demand reported during the previous day from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0413" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Month Max Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthMaxEnergyCarrierDemand is the maximum energy carrier demand reported during a month from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0414" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Month Min Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthMinEnergyCarrierDemand is the minimum energy carrier demand reported during a month from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0415" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Year Max Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentYearMaxEnergyCarrierDemand is the maximum energy carrier demand reported during a year from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0416" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Year Min Energy Carrier Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentYearMinEnergyCarrierDemand is the minimum energy carrier demand reported during a year from the heat meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0420" arraystart="2" arraycount="8" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day {{count}} Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>PreviousDayNConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0421" arraystart="2" arraycount="8" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day {{count}} Consumption Received</name>
        <description>PreviousDayNConsumptionReceived represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water received from the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0430" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Week Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentWeekConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on Monday to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentWeekConsumptionDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0431" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Week Consumption Received</name>
        <description>CurrentWeekConsumptionReceived represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water received from the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on Monday to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentWeekConsumptionReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0432" arraystart="1" arraycount="5" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Week {{count}} Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>PreviousWeekNConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises within the previous week period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the Monday to the Sunday. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0433" arraystart="1" arraycount="5" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Week {{count}} Consumption Received</name>
        <description>PreviousWeekNConsumptionReceived represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water received from the premises within the previous week period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the Monday to the Sunday. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0440" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Current Month Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the 1st of the month to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentMonthConsumptionDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0441" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Current Month Consumption Received</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthConsumptionReceived represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water received from the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the 1st of the month to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentMonthConsumptionReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0442" arraystart="1" arraycount="13" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Previous Month {{count}} Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>PreviousMonthNConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered to the premises within the previous Month period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the 1st of the month to the last day of the month. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0443" arraystart="1" arraycount="13" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Previous Month {{count}} Consumption Received</name>
        <description>PreviousMonthNConsumptionReceived represents the summed value of Energy, Gas, or Water received from the premises within the previous month period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the 1st of the month to the last day of the month. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x045C" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0x173B" default="0x0000">
        <name>Historical Freeze Time</name>
        <description>HistoricalFreezeTime (HFT) represents the time of day, in Local Time, when Historical Consumption attributes and/or Alternative Historical Consumption attributes are captured. HistoricalFreezeTime is an unsigned 16-bit value representing the hour and minutes for HFT.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0500" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x18">
        <name>Max Number Of Periods Delivered</name>
        <description>MaxNumberofPeriodsDelivered represents the maximum number of intervals the device is capable of returning in one Get Profile Response command. It is required MaxNumberofPeriodsDelivered fit within the default Fragmentation ASDU size of 128 bytes, or an optionally agreed upon larger Fragmentation ASDU size supported by both devices.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0600" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Demand Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentDemandDelivered represents the current Demand of Energy, Gas, or Water delivered at the premises. CurrentDemandDelivered may be continuously updated as new measurements are acquired, but at a minimum CurrentDemandDelivered must be updated at the end of each integration sub- period, which can be obtained by dividing the DemandIntegrationPeriod by the NumberOfDemandSubintervals.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0601" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Demand Limit</name>
        <description>DemandLimit reflects the current supply demand limit set in the meter. This value can be compared to the CurrentDemandDelivered attribute to understand if limits are being approached or exceeded.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0602" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x01" maximum="0xFF">
        <name>Demand Integration Period</name>
        <description>DemandIntegrationPeriod is the number of minutes over which the CurrentDemandDelivered attribute is calculated. Valid range is 0x01 to 0xFF. 0x00 is a reserved value.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0603" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x01" maximum="0xFF">
        <name>Number Of Demand Subintervals</name>
        <description>NumberOfDemandSubintervals represents the number of subintervals used within the DemandIntegrationPeriod. The subinterval duration (in minutes) is obtained by dividing the DemandIntegrationPeriod by the NumberOfDemandSubintervals. The CurrentDemandDelivered attribute is updated at the each of each subinterval. Valid range is 0x01 to 0xFF. 0x00 is a reserved value.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0604" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x0000" maximum="0xFFFF" default="0x003C">
        <name>Demand Limit Arm Duration</name>
        <description>An unsigned 16-bit integer that defines the length of time, in seconds, that the supply shall be disconnected if the DemandLimit attribute is enabled and the limit is exceeded. At the end of the time period the meter shall move to the ARMED status. This will allow the user to reconnect the supply.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0605" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>Load Limit Supply State</name>
        <description>The LoadLimitSupplyState attribute indicates the required status of the supply once device is in a load limit state.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0606" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00" maximum="0xFF" default="0x01">
        <name>Load Limit Counter</name>
        <description>An unsigned 8-bit integer used for counting the number of times that the demand limit has exceeded the set threshold.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0607" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>Supply Tamper State</name>
        <description>The SupplyTamperState indicates the required status of the supply following the detection of a tamper event within the metering device.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0608" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>Supply Depletion State</name>
        <description>The SupplyDepletionState indicates the required status of the supply following detection of a depleted battery within the metering device.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0609" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x00">
        <name>Supply Uncontrolled Flow State</name>
        <description>The SupplyUncontrolledFlowState indicates the required status of the supply following detection of an uncontrolled flow event within the metering device.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0700" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current No Tier Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0710" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 1 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0720" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 2 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0730" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 3 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0740" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 4 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0750" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 5 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0760" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 6 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0770" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 7 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0780" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 8 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0790" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 9 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x07A0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 10 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x07B0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 11 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x07C0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 12 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x07D0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 13 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x07E0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 14 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x07F0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 15 Block {{count}} Summation Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0800" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0xFFFF">
        <name>Generic Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0801" type="BITMAP_32_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Electricity Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0802" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0xFFFF">
        <name>Generic Flow /pressure Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0803" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0xFFFF">
        <name>Water Specific Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0804" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0xFFFF">
        <name>Heat And Cooling Specific Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0805" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0xFFFF">
        <name>Gas Specific Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0806" type="BITMAP_48_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="">
        <name>Extended Generic Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0807" type="BITMAP_16_BIT" side="server" optional="true" writable="true" reportable="true" default="0xFFFF">
        <name>Manufacture Alarm Mask</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0900" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current No Tier Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0910" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 1 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0920" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 2 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0930" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 3 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0940" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 4 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0950" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 5 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0960" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 6 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0970" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 7 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0980" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 8 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0990" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 9 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x09A0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 10 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x09B0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 11 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x09C0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 12 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x09D0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 13 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x09E0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 14 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x09F0" arraystart="1" arraycount="16"  type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Tier 15 Block {{count}} Summation Received</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A00" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF" default="0x00000000">
        <name>Bill To Date Delivered</name>
        <description>BillToDateDelivered provides a value for the costs in the current billing period. This attribute is measured in a base unit of Currency with the decimal point located as indicated by the BillDeliveredTrailingDigit attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A01" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="">
        <name>Bill To Date Time Stamp Delivered</name>
        <description>The UTC timestamp when the associated BillToDateDelivered attribute was last updated.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A02" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF" default="0x00000000">
        <name>Projected Bill Delivered</name>
        <description>ProjectedBillDelivered provides a value indicating what the estimated state of the account will be at the end of the billing period based on past consumption. This attribute is measured in a base unit of Currency with the decimal point located as indicated by the BillDeliveredTrailingDigit attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A03" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="">
        <name>Projected Bill Time Stamp Delivered</name>
        <description>The UTC timestamp when the associated ProjectedBillDelivered attribute was last updated.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A04" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Bill Delivered Trailing Digit</name>
        <description>An 8-bit BitMap used to determine where the decimal point is located in the BillToDateDelivered and ProjectedBillDelivered attributes. The most significant nibble indicates the number of digits to the right of the decimal point. The least significant nibble is reserved and shall be 0. The BillDeliveredTrailingDigit attribute represents the current active value.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A10" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF" default="0x00000000">
        <name>Bill To Date Received</name>
        <description>BillToDateReceived provides a value for the costs in the current billing period. This attribute is measured in a base unit of Currency with the decimal point located as indicated by the BillReceivedTrailingDigit attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A11" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="">
        <name>Bill To Date Time Stamp Received</name>
        <description>The UTC timestamp when the associated BillToDateReceived attribute was last updated.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A12" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF" default="0x00000000">
        <name>Projected Bill Received</name>
        <description>ProjectedBillReceived provides a value indicating what the estimated state of the account will be at the end of the billing period based on past generation. This attribute is measured in a base unit of Currency with the decimal point located as indicated by the BillReceivedTrailingDigit attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A13" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="">
        <name>Projected Bill Time Stamp Received</name>
        <description>The UTC timestamp when the associated ProjectedBillReceived attribute was last updated.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0A14" type="BITMAP_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Bill Received Trailing Digit</name>
        <description>An 8-bit BitMap used to determine where the decimal point is located in the BillToDateReceived and ProjectedBillReceived attributes. The most significant nibble indicates the number of digits to the right of the decimal point. The least significant nibble is reserved and shall be 0. The BillReceivedTrailingDigit attribute represents the current active value</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B00" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Proposed Change Supply Implementation Time</name>
        <description>The ProposedChangeImplementationTime attribute indicates the time at which a proposed change to the supply is to be implemented. If there is no change of supply pending, this attribute will be set to 0xFFFFFFFF.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B01" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Proposed Change Supply Status</name>
        <description>The ProposedChangeSupplyStatus indicates the proposed status of the supply once the change to the supply has be been implemented.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B10" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Uncontrolled Flow Threshold</name>
        <description>The Uncontrolled Flow Threshold attribute indicates the threshold above which a flow meter (e.g. Gas or Water) shall detect an uncontrolled flow. A value of 0x0000 indicates the feature in unused.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B11" type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="UnitOfMeasure" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Uncontrolled Flow Threshold Unit Of Measure</name>
        <description>The Uncontrolled Flow Threshold Unit of Measure attribute indicates the unit of measure used in conjunction with the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold attribute.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B12" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x0001">
        <name>Uncontrolled Flow Threshold Multiplier</name>
        <description>The Uncontrolled Flow Multiplier attribute indicates the multiplier, to be used in conjunction with the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold and Uncontrolled Flow Divisor attributes, to determine the true flow threshold value. A value of 0x0000 is not allowed.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B13" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x0001">
        <name>Uncontrolled Flow Threshold Divisor</name>
        <description>The Uncontrolled Flow Divisor attribute indicates the divisor, to be used in conjunction with the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold and Uncontrolled Flow Multiplier attributes, to determine the true flow threshold value. A value of 0x0000 is not allowed.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B14" type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Flow Stabilization Period</name>
        <description>The Flow Stabilisation Period attribute indicates the time given to allow the flow to stabilize. It is defined in units of tenths of a second.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0B15" type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Flow Measurement Period</name>
        <description>The Flow Measurement Period attribute indicates the period over which the flow is measured and compared against the Uncontrolled Flow Threshold attribute. It is defined in units of 1 second.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C00" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" default="0x000000">
        <name>Alternative Instantaneous Demand</name>
        <description>AlternativeInstantaneousDemand represents the current Demand delivered or received at the premises. Positive values indicate demand delivered to the premises where negative values indicate demand received from the premises. AlternativeInstantaneousDemand is updated continuously as new measurements are made. The frequency of updates to this field is specific to the metering device, but should be within the range of once every second to once every 5 seconds.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C01" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Alternative Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentDayAlternativeConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value delivered to the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, CurrentDayAlternativeConsumptionDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C02" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Alternative Consumption Received</name>
        <description>CurrentDayAlternativeConsumptionReceived represents the summed value received from the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, CurrentDayAlternativeConsumptionReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C03" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Alternative Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>PreviousDayAlternativeConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value delivered to the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Alternative Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, PreviousDayAlternativeConsumptionDelivered is updated every HFT. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C04" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Alternative Consumption Received</name>
        <description>PreviousDayAlternativeConsumptionReceived represents the summed value received from the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If optionally provided, PreviousDayAlternativeConsumptionReceived is updated every HFT. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C05" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Alternative Partial Profile Interval Start Time Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentAlternativePartialProfileIntervalStartTimeDelivered represents the start time of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity delivered.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C06" type="UTCTIME" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Alternative Partial Profile Interval Start Time Received</name>
        <description>CurrentAlternativePartialProfileIntervalStartTimeReceived represents the start time of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity received.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C07" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Alternative Partial Profile Interval Value Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentAlternativePartialProfileIntervalValueDelivered represents the value of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity delivered.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C08" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Alternative Partial Profile Interval Value Received</name>
        <description>CurrentAlternativePartialProfileIntervalValueReceived represents the value of the current Load Profile interval being accumulated for commodity received.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C09" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Alternative Max Pressure</name>
        <description>CurrentDayAlternativeMaxPressure is the maximum pressure reported during a day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C0A" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Alternative Min Pressure</name>
        <description>CurrentDayAlternativeMinPressure is the minimum pressure reported during a day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C0B" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Alternative Max Pressure</name>
        <description>PreviousDayAlternativeMaxPressure represents the maximum pressure reported during previous day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C0C" type="UNSIGNED_48_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Alternative Min Pressure</name>
        <description>PreviousDayAlternativeMinPressure represents the minimum pressure reported during previous day from the water or gas meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C0D" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Day Alternative Max Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentDayAlternativeMaxDemand represents the maximum demand or rate of delivered value of Energy, Gas, or Water being utilized at the premises.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C0E" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day Alternative Max Demand</name>
        <description>PreviousDayAlternativeMaxDemand represents the maximum demand or rate of delivered value of Energy, Gas, or Water being utilized at the premises.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C0F" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Month Alternative Max Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthAlternativeMaxDemand is the maximum demand reported during a month from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C10" type="SIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Year Alternative Max Demand</name>
        <description>CurrentYearAlternativeMaxDemand is the maximum demand reported during a year from the meter.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C20" arraystart="2" arraycount="6" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day {{count}} Alternative Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>PreviousDayNAlternativeConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value delivered to the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C21" arraystart="2" arraycount="6" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Day {{count}} Alternative Consumption Received</name>
        <description>PreviousDayNAlternativeConsumptionReceived represents the summed value received from the premises within the previous 24 hour period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT). If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C30" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Week Alternative Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentWeekAlternativeConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value delivered to the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on Monday to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentWeekAlternativeConsumptionDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C31" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Current Week Alternative Consumption Received</name>
        <description>CurrentWeekAlternativeConsumptionReceived represents the summed value received from the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on Monday to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentWeekAlternativeConsumptionReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C32" arraystart="1" arraycount="5" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Week {{count}} Alternative Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>PreviousWeekNAlternativeConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value delivered to the premises within the previous week period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the Monday to the Sunday. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C33" arraystart="1" arraycount="5" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_24_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false">
        <name>Previous Week {{count}} Alternative Consumption Received</name>
        <description>PreviousWeekNAlternativeConsumptionReceived represents the summed value received from the premises within the previous week period starting at the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the Monday to the Sunday. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C40" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Current Month Alternative Consumption Delivered</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthAlternativeConsumptionDelivered represents the summed value delivered to the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the 1st of the month to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentMonthAlternativeConsumptionDelivered is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C41" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Current Month Alternative Consumption Received</name>
        <description>CurrentMonthAlternativeConsumptionReceived represents the summed value received from the premises since the Historical Freeze Time (HFT) on the 1st of the month to the last HFT read. If optionally provided, CurrentMonthAlternativeConsumptionReceived is updated continuously as new measurements are made. If the optional HFT attribute is not available, default to midnight local time.</description>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C42" arraystart="1" arraycount="13" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Previous Month {{count}} Alternative Consumption Delivered</name>
    </attribute>
    <attribute code="0x0C43" arraystart="1" arraycount="13" arraystep="2" type="UNSIGNED_32_BIT_INTEGER" side="server" optional="false" writable="false" reportable="false" minimum="0x00000000" maximum="0xFFFFFFFF">
        <name>Previous Month {{count}} Alternative Consumption Received</name>
    </attribute>

    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="GetProfileStatusEnum">
        <name>Get Profile Status</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Success">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Undefined Interval Channel Requested">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Interval Channel Not Supported">
        </value>
        <value code="0x03" name="Invalid End Time">
        </value>
        <value code="0x04" name="More Periods Requested Than Can Be Returned">
        </value>
        <value code="0x05" name="No Intervals Available For The Requested Time">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="IntervalChannelEnum">
        <name>Interval Channel</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Consumption Delivered">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Consumption Received">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="IntervalPeriodEnum">
        <name>Interval Period</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Daily">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Minutes 60">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Minutes 30">
        </value>
        <value code="0x03" name="Minutes 15">
        </value>
        <value code="0x04" name="Minutes 10">
        </value>
        <value code="0x05" name="Minutes 7p 5">
        </value>
        <value code="0x06" name="Minutes 5">
        </value>
        <value code="0x07" name="Minutes 2p 5">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="UnitOfMeasureEnum">
        <name>Unit Of Measure</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Kilo Watt Hours">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Cubic Meter Per Hour">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Cubic Feet Per Hour">
        </value>
        <value code="0x03" name="Centum Cubic Feet Per Hour">
        </value>
        <value code="0x04" name="Us Gallons Per Hour">
        </value>
        <value code="0x05" name="Imperial Gallons Per Hour">
        </value>
        <value code="0x06" name="Bt Us Or Btu Per Hour">
        </value>
        <value code="0x07" name="Liters Or Liters Per Hour">
        </value>
        <value code="0x08" name="Kpa Gauge">
        </value>
        <value code="0x09" name="Kpa Absolute">
        </value>
        <value code="0x0A" name="Mcf Or Mcf Per Second">
        </value>
        <value code="0x0B" name="Unitless">
        </value>
        <value code="0x0C" name="Mj Or Mj Per Second">
        </value>
        <value code="0x0D" name="K Var Or K Var Hours">
        </value>
        <value code="0x80" name="Kilo Watt Hours Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x81" name="Cubic Meter Per Hour Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x82" name="Cubic Feet Per Hour Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x83" name="Centum Cubic Feet Per Hour Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x84" name="Us Gallons Per Hour Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x85" name="Imperial Gallons Per Hour Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x86" name="Bt Us Or Btu Per Hour Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x87" name="Liters Or Liters Per Hour Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x88" name="Kpa Guage Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x89" name="Kpa Absolute Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x8A" name="Mcf Or Mcf Per Second Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x8B" name="Unitless Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x8C" name="Mj Or Mj Per Second Bcd">
        </value>
        <value code="0x8D" name="K Var Or K Var Hours Bcd">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="MeteringSupplyStatusEnum">
        <name>Metering Supply Status</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Supply Off">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Supply Off Armed">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Supply On">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="ProposedSupplyStatusEnum">
        <name>Proposed Supply Status</name>
        <value code="0x01" name="Supply Off Armed">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Supply On">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SampleTypeEnum">
        <name>Sample Type</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Consumption Delivered">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="BITMAP_32_BIT" class="SnapshotCauseBitmap">
        <name>Snapshot Cause</name>
        <value code="0x00000001" name="General">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000002" name="End Of Billing Period">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000004" name="End Of Block Period">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000008" name="Change Of Tariff Information">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000010" name="Change Of Price Matrix">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000020" name="Change Of Block Thresholds">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000040" name="Change Of Cv">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000080" name="Change Of Cf">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000100" name="Change Of Calendar">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000200" name="Critical Peak Pricing">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000400" name="Manually Triggered From Client">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00000800" name="End Of Resolve Period">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00001000" name="Change Of Tenancy">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00002000" name="Change Of Supplier">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00004000" name="Change Of Mode">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00008000" name="Debt Payment">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00010000" name="Scheduled Snapshot">
        </value>
        <value code="0x00020000" name="Ota Firmware Download">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SnapshotConfirmationEnum">
        <name>Snapshot Confirmation</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Accepted">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Snapshot Cause Not Supported">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SnapshotPayloadTypeEnum">
        <name>Snapshot Payload Type</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Tou Information Set Delivered Registers">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Tou Information Set Received Registers">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Block Tier Information Set Delivered">
        </value>
        <value code="0x03" name="Block Tier Information Set Received">
        </value>
        <value code="0x04" name="Tou Information Set Delivered Registers No Billing">
        </value>
        <value code="0x05" name="Tou Information Set Received Register No Billings">
        </value>
        <value code="0x06" name="Block Tier Information Set Delivered No Billing">
        </value>
        <value code="0x07" name="Block Tier Information Set Received No Billing">
        </value>
        <value code="0x80" name="Data Unavailable">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="BITMAP_8_BIT" class="SupplyControlBitsBitmap">
        <name>Supply Control Bits</name>
        <value code="0x01" name="Acknowledge Required">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="SupplyStatusEnum">
        <name>Supply Status</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Supply Off">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Supply Off Armed">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Supply On">
        </value>
        <value code="0x03" name="Supply Unchanged">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="BITMAP_8_BIT" class="MeteringDeviceTypeEnum">
        <name>Metering Device Type</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Electric Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Gas Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Water Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x03" name="Thermal Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x04" name="Pressure Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x05" name="Heat Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x06" name="Cooling Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x80" name="Mirrored Gas Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x81" name="Mirrored Water Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x82" name="Mirrored Thermal Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x83" name="Mirrored Pressure Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x84" name="Mirrored Heat Metering">
        </value>
        <value code="0x85" name="Mirrored Cooling Metering">
        </value>
    </constant>
    <constant type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT" class="TemperatureUnitOfMeasureEnum">
        <name>Temperature Unit Of Measure</name>
        <value code="0x00" name="Degrees Kelvin">
        </value>
        <value code="0x01" name="Degrees Celsius">
        </value>
        <value code="0x02" name="Degrees Fahrenheit">
        </value>
        <value code="0x80" name="Degrees Kelvin BCD">
        </value>
        <value code="0x81" name="Degrees Celsius BCD">
        </value>
        <value code="0x82" name="Degrees Fahrenheit BCD">
        </value>
    </constant>

    <struct class="SnapshotResponsePayload">
        <name>Snapshot Response Payload</name>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Snapshot Schedule ID</name>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT">
            <name>Snapshot Schedule Confirmation</name>
        </field>
    </struct>
    <struct class="SnapshotSchedulePayload">
        <name>Snapshot Schedule Payload</name>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Snapshot Schedule ID</name>
        </field>
        <field type="UTCTIME">
            <name>Snapshot Start Time</name>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_24_BIT">
            <name>Snapshot Schedule</name>
        </field>
        <field type="ENUMERATION_8_BIT">
            <name>Snapshot Payload Type</name>
        </field>
        <field type="BITMAP_32_BIT">
            <name>Snapshot Cause</name>
        </field>
    </struct>
    <struct class="NotificationCommandSubPayload">
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Cluster ID</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit integer that denotes the Cluster id of the Notification flag that will be configured for this Notification scheme.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_16_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Manufacturer Code</name>
            <description>An unsigned 16-bit integer that denotes the Manufacturer Code to be used with these command IDs, that are configured for this Notification flag within this Notification scheme.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Number Of Commands</name>
            <description>An unsigned 8-bit integer that indicates the number of command identifiers contained within this sub payload.</description>
        </field>
        <field type="UNSIGNED_8_BIT_INTEGER">
            <name>Command IDs</name>
            <description>An unsigned 8-bit integer that denotes the command that is to be used. The command id should be used with the cluster id to reference the command(s).</description>
        </field>
	</struct>
</cluster>
